A Guide to the Records of the Office of Academic Affairs, 1961-1977 (bulk 1965-1976)
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Records of the Office of Academic Affairs, 1961-1977 (bulk 1965-1976)
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 5/1/2
84 Cubic Feet; 60 boxes
This collection consists primarily of correspondence and records from the Office of Academic Affairs at Virginia Tech. The papers reflect the many changes at Virginia Tech as it became a university (approved by legislature on June 23, 1970) and as the roles of faculty and the participation of students within the university were defined. There also are materials relating to campus disorders and dissent during 1970 to 1971. Materials are from Leslie F. Malpass' tenure as Vice-President for Academic Affairs (1968-1974); from Alfred H. Krebs' tenure as director of Summer School, as Assistant Vice President of Academic Affairs under Malpass, and as acting Vice President for Academic Affairs from August 1974 until September 1975; and from Donald C. Darnton's tenure as Director of Special Programs, which also was under the Office of Academic Affairs.
Darnton, Donald C.
Krebs, Alfred H., 1920-2012
Malpass, Leslie F., 1922-2011
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Source of Acquisition
The Records of the Office of Academic Affairs were transferred to Special Collections and University Archives in 1990.
Administrative History
The Office of Vice-President of Academic Affairs was established in 1966. The title changed to Provost by the Board of Visitors on November 5, 1976. It evolved into the Senior Vice President and Provost, and in 2015, it became the Executive Vice President and Provost.
Biographical Note - Leslie F. Malpass
Leslie F. Malpass (1922 - 2011) studied at the University of Cincinnati and Cincinnati Conservatory of Music. He earned degrees in psychology at the University of Syracuse, a B.A. in 1947, a MA in 1949, and a Ph.D. in 1952.
Malpass served as Dean of the Virginia Tech College of Arts and Sciences from 1965 until 1968, when he became Vice President for Academic Affairs. In this position, he was responsible for the academic functioning of the university.
In August 1974, Krebs left Virginia Tech to assume the post of President of Western Illinois University (WIU). During his tenure (1974-1887), he supervised the construction of the architecturally notable University Library, which was renamed in his honor and rededicated as the Leslie F. Malpass Library in 2001.
Malpass wrote numerous book, monographs, and refereed journal articles. Besides his teaching activities, he was involved in the planning and organization of the Special Olympics. He also was a consultant to the development of the Peace Corps.
Sources:
WIU Mourns Passing of Former President Leslie F. Malpass, March 17, 2011
Hall-Wynne Funeral Service memorial obituary
Biographical Note - Alfred H. Krebs
Alfred H. Krebs (1920-2012) was educated at Cornell University, earning a B.A. in 1941, an M.A. in 1943, and a Ph.D. in 1950. He held positions in agricultural education at the University of Illinois and the University of Maryland, until joining Virginia Tech as professor and head of agricultural education in 1969.
Krebs was named Director of Summer School in 1970 and Assistant Vice President for Academic Affairs in 1972. When Dr. Malpass left Virginia Tech in 1974, Dr. Krebs served as Acting Vice President for Academic Affairs until John D. Wilson assumed the post in September 1975.
Next, Krebs was named Acting Vice President for Special Projects and then Vice President for Special Projects until his appointment in 1977 as Vice President for Administration. He succeeded Stuart K. Cassell in this position.
Krebs retired in 1981.
Biographical Note - Donald Charles Darnton
Donald Charles Darnton was Associate Professor of Economics and Director of Special Academic Programs at Virginia Tech. He earned an A.B. from William and Mary in 1953 and an M.A. in 1956 and Ph.D. in 1961, both from the University of Michigan. He came to Virginia Tech in 1965.
Scope and Content
This collection consists primarily of correspondence and records from the Office of Academic Affairs at Virginia Tech. The bulk is from Malpass' tenure as Vice-President for Academic Affairs (1968-1974), but there also are materials from Alfred H. Krebs' tenure as director of Summer School and as Assistant Vice President of Academic Affairs under Malpass and from Donald C. Darnton's tenure as Director of Special Programs, which also was under the Office of Academic Affairs. There are also materials from Alfred H. Krebs' tenure as acting Vice President for Academic Affairs from August 1974 when Dr. Malpass left until John D. Wilson assumed the post in September 1975.
The papers reflect the many changes at Virginia Tech as it became a university (approved by legislature on June 23, 1970) and as the roles of faculty and the participation of students within the university were defined. There also are materials relating to campus disorders and dissent during 1970 to 1971. There are materials dealing with the College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, the College of Architecture, the College of Arts and Sciences, the College of Business, the College of Education, the College of Engineering, the College of Education, the College of Home Economics, Graduate School, Extension and Research Divisions, Commission on Undergraduate Studies, Commission on Student Affairs, University Council, the Computing Center, the library, Deans' meetings, proposed degree programs, the Center for Interdisciplinary Research, Traffic Committee, admissions, enrollment, Center for Economic Education, Water Resources Center, Learning Resources Center, Committee on Academic Schedule, Black Studies, Summer School and Summer Orientation, and Upward Bound. There also is material on the Study Abroad Committee, Visiting Scholars Program, Task Force for Innovation in Instruction, Telecommunications Council, University Space Research Association, budget, Urban Interdisciplinary Study Council, the Ellis L. Phillips Foundation, space at the university, and Faculty Senate and Handbook and other faculty issues. Records also include correspondence with the State Council of Higher Education for Virginia.
Arrangement
The Records of the Office of Academic Affairs are arranged in series by subject matter. Within each series, materials are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Some series of records (Series VII, X-XII) and correspondence have subseries organized by college or administrative unit. Subseries are arranged alphabetically by department or subject matter.
For the most part, original folder headings, where available, have been used. Some folder headings were added to assist researchers in finding materials.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Archival Material
See also the Records of the Office of the Vice President for Academic Affairs and the Office of the Vice President for Special Projects, Alfred Krebs, RG 5/1/2/1 from Virginia Tech Special Collections and University Archives.
Rights Statement for Archival Description
The guide to the Records of the Office of Academic Affairs by Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, is licensed under a CC0 (https://creativecommons.org/share-your- work/public-domain/cc0/).
Index Terms
Subjects:
Faculty; University Archives; University History
Organizations:
State Council of Higher Education for Virginia; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. College of Arts and Sciences; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. College of Engineering (1964-); Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. College of Business (1972-1995); Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. College of Education; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. College of Agriculture and Life Sciences; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. College of Home Economics (1964-1982); Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Graduate School; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. College of Architecture (1974-1978); Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. College of Architecture and Urban Studies (1978-)
People:
Darnton, Donald C.; Krebs, Alfred H., 1920-2012; Malpass, Leslie F., 1922-2011
Contents List
- Series I: Leslie Malpass, Personal, 1966-1970
  - Peace Corps, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Presbyterian Church - Blacksburg, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Speech Material (4 folders), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
- Series II: Ellis Foundation, 1961-1973
  - Ellis L. Phillips Foundation, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ellis L. Phillips Foundation, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ellis L. Phillips Foundation, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ellis L. Phillips Foundation (2 folders), 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Ellis L. Phillips Foundation, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ellis L. Phillips Foundation, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ellis L. Phillips Foundation, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ellis L. Phillips Foundation, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ellis L. Phillips Foundation, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence - Phillips Foundation, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Series III: Records and Correspondence, 1965-1966
  - Academic Council, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Athletic Association, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Project Appalachia: Cost Accounts, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Purchase Orders and Travel Reimbursement (2 folders), 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
  - Virginia Division of Industrial Planning and VPI - Contract and Interim Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Series IV: Records and Correspondence, 1966-1967
  - Academic Policies, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Athletic Association, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Committee of Deans, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Faculty: Lists, Positions, Compensation Plan, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - University Council, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Visiting Scholars, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Series V: Records and Correspondence, 1967-1968
  - Agriculture - Dairy Science Department - Progress Review, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Athletic Association, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Chambers, Dwight, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 31A)
  - Council of Deans, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Educational Aid - State Employees, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Faculty Lists and Positions, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Development Proposal - Geological Sciences, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - NASULGC - Council for Academic Affairs - Minutes, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Office of Institutional Research, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Registration, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Research, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - University Council, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - University Services and Auxiliary Enterprises, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Series VI: Records and Correspondence, 1968-1969
  - Academic Policies, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Agriculture, College of, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Arts and Sciences, College of - Education, (2 folders), 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Arts and Sciences, College of - English, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Arts and Sciences, College of - Fine Arts, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Arts and Sciences, College of - Foreign Languages, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Arts and Sciences, College of - Geological Sciences, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Development Proposal - Geological Sciences, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Proposal for Achieving Excellence in the Geological Sciences at VPI, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Athletic Association, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Board of Visitors, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Council of Deans, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Deans' Meetings - Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Office of the Dean for Men and Women's Residence Program, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Department of Education, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - EDUCOM, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Extension, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Faculty Senate - By Laws, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - GTA - Positions, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Arts and Sciences - Health and Physical Education, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Ideas for VPI, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Office of Institutional Research, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Library, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - National Association of Universities and Land Grant Colleges, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Pass/Fail, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Research Division - Correspondence (2 folders), 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 27-28)
  - Self-Study - Letters, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Study Abroad Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Study Abroad, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - University Council, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - University Council Meeting - Minutes, (2 folders), 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 33-34)
  - University Development, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - J. Hoge Tyler Papers, Development and Alumni Interrelations, 1968-1969
  - University Professorships, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - University Services and Auxiliary Enterprises, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Vice Presidents, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - YMCA, 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Series VII: Records and Correspondence, 1969-1970
  - Subseries A: College of Agriculture, 1969-1970
    - Agricultural Economics, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Agricultural Engineering, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Agronomy, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Anaerobe Laboratory, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Division of Animal and Veterinary Medicine, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Animal Science (3 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 6-8)
    - Division of Basic Sciences, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Biochemistry and Nutrition, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Consulting, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence (2 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
    - Dairy Science, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Enrollment Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Entomology, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Faculty Association, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Faculty Candidates, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Food Science and Technology, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Grants and Fellowships, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Horticulture, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Plant Pathology and Physiology (2 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
    - Poultry Science, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Agriculture Program, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Research Activities, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Space, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Veterinary Pet Insurance, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Veterinary Science, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Subseries B: College of Architecture, 1969-1970
    - Architecture (4 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 30-31, Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Articles and Research, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Consulting Activities, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Enrollment Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Candidates, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Plans and Projections, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: College of Arts and Science, 1969-1970
    - Biology, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Chairman's Meetings - Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Chemistry, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Computer Science, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Consulting, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence (2 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
    - Dean, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - [There is no folder 16 in box 4.] (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Education (2 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
    - Education - Dean Search Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - English (2 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
    - Enrollment, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Faculty Association, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Faculty Candidates,, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Fine Arts, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - "Fine Arts at VPI", 1969 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Foreign Languages, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Geological Sciences, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Geological Sciences - Amphibole-Proxene Symposium, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Development Proposal - Geological Science, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Grants and Fellowships, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Health and Physical Education Masters Program Proposal, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Health and Physical Education, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - History, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Mathematics, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Mathematics, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Philosophy and Religion, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Physics (2 folders), 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 38, Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Political Science, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Psychology Department, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Research Activities, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - ROTC Air Force, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - ROTC - Army, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Sociology Department, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Space, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Statistics Department (2 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
    - Theatre Arts and Speech Curriculum Proposal, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Theatre Arts Degree Proposal, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Undergraduate Student Matters, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Visiting Scholars, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Subseries D: College of Business, 1969-1970
    - Accounting, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Business Administration, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Business Extension, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Consulting Activities, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - General Correspondence (2 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
    - Economics, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Enrollment Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Grants and Fellowships, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Publications, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Student Matters, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Subseries E: College of Engineering, 1969-1970
    - Aerospace Engineering, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Chemical Energy, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Civil Engineering, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - College Development and Reorganization, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Consulting Activities, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence (2 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
    - Dean, College of Engineering, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Electrical Engineering, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Electrowriter and Telecommunications, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Engineering, College of, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Engineering Fundamentals, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Engineering Mechanics, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Enrollment Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Faculty Candidates (3 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 15-17)
    - Faculty Publications, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Grants and Fellowships, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Industrial Engineering, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Mechanical Engineering, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Metals and Ceramic Engineering, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Mining Engineering, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - News Report - National Academy of Science, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - A Proposal for the Development of VPI, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - "The Objectives and the Tools" - J. Lukasiewicz
    - Research Activities (2 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 26-27)
    - Student Papers, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Subseries F: College of Home Economics, 1969-1970
    - Clothing, Textiles and Related Arts, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Consulting Activities, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - General Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Enrollment Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Faculty Candidates, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Grants and Fellowships, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Human Nutrition and Foods, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Management and Housing and Family Development, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Subseries G: Graduate School, 1969-1970
    - General Correspondence (2 folders), 1968-1970 (Box 6, Folder 37-38)
    - Graduate Assembly, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Enrollment and Reports, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Graduate Center, Naval Weapons Lab, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Graduate Center, Reston, Virginia, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Development - Reston Research, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Graduate Center South Boston, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Graduate Student housing, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Grants, Fellowships and Funding Agencies, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Subseries H: Special Programs, 1969-1970
    - Center for Environmental Studies, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Center for Numerical Methods in Engineering, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Center for Study of Public Choice, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Special Academic Program - Dr. Darnton, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Subseries I: Extension and Research Division, 1969-1970
    - Adult Education CEC, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Business Extension Program, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - College Projections (2 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
    - College Projections, 1963-1969 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Consulting Requests, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Cooperative Education Meeting, Rochester, NY, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Cooperative Education Meeting, Tampa, Florida, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Co-op Program (2 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
    - English Speaking Union, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Extension - General Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Extension Grants, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Faculty Exchange Program, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Ford Foundation, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - 4-H Activities, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Institute for Environmental Inquiry and Planning (IEIP), 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - International Farm Youth Exchange Program, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - International Studies Program, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Learning Resources Center, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Libraries Faculty Loan Policies, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Monthly Calendar, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - NASA NGR 47-004-006 Progress Report No.8 (2 folders), 1969 (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
    - Nutrition Program in Home Economics Special Needs, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Presidents' Workshop on Cooperative Education, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Radiation Safety Committee, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Research Council Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Research Division Annual Report, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Research Division Correspondence (2 folders), 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 14-15)
    - Deanship - Research Division, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Rural Affairs Study Commission, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Social Welfare Research Institute, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Southern Regional Education Board (SREB): Graduate Education in Agricultural Sciences (Kellogg Project), 1969 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - State Museum of Science, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - State Technical Services, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Study Abroad Program, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - THEMIS Program, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 23)